N S

# BIOGRAPHY

I am a 21 years old Information Systems Engineer from Heredia, Costa Rica. I think knowledge is one of the most important resources, therefore, I consider research and innovation one of the most important tools of a modern professional. I like to read science fiction, discover new places, cook and black and white photography. I also like to read and write technical articles.

ENGINEER

/romogo17

in

/in/romogo17

M

/@romogo17 /romogo17

y

# EXPERIENCE

# RESEARCH ASSISTANT

National University Costa Rica | October 2017 - November2018

Project: Databases for the storage and analysis of digital mammograms.

# TEACHING ASSISTANT

National University Costa Rica | February 2018 - November 2018 Class: Database Design and Implementation

# DEVELOPER

Santo Domingo Municipality | Febrero 2017 - Junio 2018 Development of the Municipal Vehicles Control System

(COVEM) for the Santo Domingo Municipality.

# **EDUCATION**

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN INFORMA-TION SYSTEMS ENGINEERING

National University Costa Rica | 2015 - 2018

MACHINE LEARNING A-Z: HANDS-ON PYTHON & R IN DATA SCIENCE

Udemy | December 2017

DIPLOMA IN INFORMATICS APPLICATIONS PROGRAMMING

National University Costa Rica | 2015 - 2017

HONORS GRADUATE

Santa María de Guadalupe High School | 2010 - 2014

# LANGUAGES

Born in Costa Rica, my native tongue is Spanish. English is my second language.





# ACKNOWLEDGMENTS & CERTIFICATES

# 2018

Appreciation Certificate - Infocontexto 2018 | Informatics School

Scrum Fundamentals Certified  $\mid$  Scrum-STUDY

2017

Participation Certificate - Introduction to IoT | IEEE Communications Society

# 2015

Best Entrance Average Grade to the Exact and Natural Sciences Faculty | National University Costa Rica

# 2014

Seccond Best Average Grade in my Class | Santa María de Guadalupe High School

Best Institutional Average Grade in the UCR-UNA Entrance Exam | Santa María de Guadalupe High School

# **SOFT SKILLS**

# LEADERSHIP AND TEAMWORK

Through the years, I've had the opportunity to successfully lead several work teams, this is why leadership is a skill I've developed with time. Moreover, I strongly believe that teamwork is one of the most important tools for a professional, because it allows a team to be more than the sum of its parts.

# CREATIVITY AND INNOVATION

I consider creativity of great value in an industry that grows and reinvents itself at a fast pace. This is why creativity is so important, as it allows to solve problems in a more efficient, innovative manner.

#### RESPONSIBILITY AND HONESTY

I am an extremely responsible person with a great concern for delivering added value to my work. Moreover, I consider myself a very critic and honest person.

# INTERESTS

# MACHINE LEARNING

Deep Learning Convolutional Neural Networks Artificial Intelligence Business Intelligence Computer Vision

#### BIOINFORMATICS

#### RESEARCH

I am fond of academic research, specially in the fields of Deep Learning, High Performance Computing and Bioinformatics

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES / MARKUP / SCRIPTING

Java
Javascript

Python
C#
C

HTML CSS

R Go Scheme Bash Powershell

# DATABASES

C + +

PostgreSQL Oracle MySQL SQL Server

MongoDB

# OTHERS

Git &
Github

Scrum

Docker

GraphQL

Photoshop Illustrator

LaTeX Markdown

# REFERENCES

Johnny Villalobos Murillo | Professor at the National University Costa Rica

(+506) 8303 6556 | johnny.villalobos@gmail.com

